Hello friends, I am your personal
finance coach Ashutosh. Friends, if you are
looking for health insurance for your parents
or for your children, then
it can be quite
confusing because the undertaking of our
normal health insurance is
so strict that many times we are
not able to take this health insurance from our parents. Secondly,
these health insurances do
not provide coverage in higher incomes. Secondly, their premium is also
very high. In such a situation,
we should look towards senior citizen specific insurance
plans. Friends, these plans are
very affordable and their
undertaking is very lenient
and we can get them easily. Friends,
one such plan is ICC Lombard's
Golden Shield Health Insurance Plan.
In today's video, we
will review this plan and will know about all its benefits and features.
So stay tuned with this video till further notice.
Friends, if we talk about hospital, then in-
patient hospital related
holidays, whatever medical treatment is there,
all the hospitals which are above 24 hours,  There will be a tax on room rent,
friends, for policies of ₹ 10 lakh and less,
rooms will be available on twin sharing basis.
For policies above 10 lakh, up
to a single private room will be available.
Apart from this, if we are talking about day care procedures and
treatments, then friends, such
treatments which are done
in a few hours' procedures due to advancement of technology, do
not require a 24-hour hospital for them, such treatments are also covered
in the policy. Talking about modern treatment,
friends, modern treatment
is also covered in a defined list in which
bronchial thermo plastic ion, all these
treatments are included in the category of modern treatment,
which is covered in this plan.
Apart from this, charges of 60 days for pre-hospitalization
and 180 days for post-hospitalization
are available. Friends, free
hospitalization means that if you have been
hospitalized for any disease
and if you have incurred any medical expenses related to this disease
before being hospitalized, then those expenses up to 60 days will be covered
in this policy. Similarly, if
we recover from the hospital  We are discharged and there are
medical expenses related to the disease for which we were admitted in the hospital.
After discharge, UPTU will charge up to 180 days.
In this policy, if we
talk about donor express, then
whatever
medical expenses are incurred on the donor in case of transplant, up to Rs. 10 lakh will be
charged. The next benefit
is domestic hospital
fertilization, which we take at home. If the
patient's condition is so critical that he
cannot be admitted to any hospital
or if a bed is not available in any hospital, then
when we do hospitalization at home, then
we call it domicile hospitalization. There are
charges for this also in this policy.
Apart from this, home treatment,
friends, there are many treatments
like chemotherapy or dialysis,
for such treatments the doctor advises us
that you can do this treatment at home, so
for such home treatments
also, charges of up to five percent will be
available. Apart from this, in-patient AYUSH
hospital, such alternative treatments like
Ayurvedic, Yoga, Unani, Siddha, Homeopathy
related to this,  Also, in-patient treatment
means that the hospital will be taxed,
charges up to ₹10000 will be available,
apart from this, there are charges for ambulances in this plan as well,
which will now be available to us,
talking about other features, friends,
in this plan we get short-term insurance ranging from ₹5 lakh to ₹50 lakh,
in this we can take
policies of one year, two years and three years together, the
minimum entry period for this plan is
56 years, there is no maximum entry period,
now we can enter this plan at any time,
along with this
we get the option of live long renewable, the
next benefit is additional friends,
in this plan we get a
guaranteed cumulative bonus of 10% on
every claim free air because
now the maximum will be available up to 100%,
inside benefit up to hundred percent will be
available, but here it will be for unlimited life,
meaning that if you have
already taken hospitalization for any illness, then this
year if  If you are taking hospitalization for this, then
you will not get the reset benefits. The
next benefit is Enhanced Annual
Function Road Traffic Accident. If there is an
accident due to road traffic and
you are hospitalized, then
whatever basic benefit you have will be doubled.
Talking about preventive health checkup for your treatment, the company has a free
defined package which you can avail
on network providers or other
panel health service centers. Apart from this, if you
get the pneumonia vaccine, you
get a discount of 2.5% on your premium.
Friends, a very good benefit of this plan
is the Care Management Program.
In this Care Management Program, you will get
practical consultation on second eye opinion,
Health Management Program Care
Calls, Google incentives on outcome of
preventive health,
yoga meditation session, completion of target
steps, medical ward, health assistant,
ambulance assistant, discount on service
and products like this. Apart from this,
we get some tax benefits in area 80d.
If your age is less than 60 then deduction up to 25000
and
You can avail deduction of up to Rs 50,000 from Rs 60 to Abohar. Friends, in this plan
we get to see zone wise premium, in
which Zone A includes Daily NCR,
Mumbai, Thane district, Navi Mumbai, Gujarat and
Kolkata.
Hyderabad, Secunderabad, Chhattisgarh, Madhya
Pradesh, Daman and Diu, Dadar Nagar Haveli, Goa,
Maharashtra, Mumbai and Thane district are included.
Apart from this, Zone S1 India is included.
Talking about optional expenses, we
get a Clamp Protector Rider in this.
Friends, there are many such expenses
which come in the non-medical list, which are
not taxed in our normal health insurance. If we take this rider, then the
charges for such non-medical items like PPT, Kids Series, Gloves, Cotton, etc. also start getting taxed in our policy. The
next rider is
Modification of Base Payment. Friends,
in this plan we get a mandatory 50%
payment in but with the policy,
but by taking this rider we can reduce our payment
by 50% to 50%, 30% and 20%.
Apart from this, we also get voluntary  We
get the option of deductible, friends,
in detective we have to
pay the initial amount of deductible ourselves
and the remaining
amount after that is borne by the insurance company,
like in a payment we have cost
sharing, suppose if the payment is 30% then
80% of the bill will be borne by us and 70% by the
insurance company, but
in detective if our deductible is ₹1 lakh then even if
our
bill is ₹2 lakh, we will have to pay the initial ₹1 lakh
and whatever remaining balance is there, the
insurance company will pay the same.  So
friends, in this plan, we get the option of a voluntary 20%
deductible. The
option of a 20% deductible is
very good for those who
already have a corporate policy or a
PSU policy whose sum injured is low.
We can pay the initial bill from the base policy through
our PSU or corporate policy
and pay any remaining balance from
this policy. We can
deduct this way. Apart from this,
we get another rider called Care Management Plus
Program, in which we get the option of healthcare
professional, health coach, health update to
family member, outpatient consultation, routine
diagnostic and minor procedures, and
nursing home.
Friends, if we talk about the conditions of this plan, then
this plan
can only take the maximum, and the premium
of this policy will be
calculated according to whichever elder member is in it. Talking about the base co-payment,
friends, in this plan, we get a
base co-payment of 50%.
Friends, in this plan, there are
sub-limits for some procedures and medical conditions element,
such as cataract.  For file legs,
we will have to pay ₹25000 for shot,
₹50000 for abortion and ₹75000 for abortion above 20 lakh.
Apart from this, there will be a capping of 50 thousand for cerebrovascular and
cardiovascular disorders, cancer including
more radio and local renal
complications and disorders of long term.
Apart from this, there will be a capping of ₹51059 for robotic surgery,
₹175000 for 20 lakh
and
₹20000 for show-off. Friends, there
is a free off period of 15 days in this policy, which
means that you can cancel your policy within 15 days of taking the policy.
Talking about waiting periods, friends, the initial
waiting period is 30 days. There is a waiting period for
pre-existing diseases, which means there is
two days for the diseases which you already have.  There
is a waiting period of 2 years and
for specific or long growing diseases there
is a waiting period of 2 years like hernia,
track ulcer etc. Friends,
we get to see a camping in this plane if
you do not have any free existing disease,
in such a case a
waiting period of 90 days will be applicable for hypertension, diabetes and cardiac conditions.
Friends, this was the
big picture of ICC Home Guard Golden Shilplane.
Friends, this is a very good plane which
you can buy for your parents.
Friends, if you have any doubt related to this plane,
you can ask by commenting below.
If you liked this video and
you want to support our work, then
friends, you can also buy this policy with us, in
which we recommend you a right product according to your financial and
medical condition, along with this,
we also have after sales services, in which
our dedicated team gives you complete
guidance and helps
you in settling the claim tension-free.
Friends, like the video and subscribe to the channel.
in the next video thanks